# Justin Vallelonga

**Software Engineer** 

1538 Chambers Dr. Boulder, CO 80305

719.433.8854 jlvallelonga@gmail.com

# **Personal Summary**

Justin is a hard worker with strong problem solving skills. He is creative and very detail oriented. Justin has been in the software industry full time for eight years, but has been developing software for over 10. He has a natural ability for intuitive user interface design, and he is familiar with a wide range of technologies.

## **Skills**

Proficient in Elixir, Ruby, JavaScript, Python, PHP, Java, C++, HTML, CSS, C#, and VB.

Experienced in Linux, Mac, and Windows environments.

Familiar with Scrum and Kanban.

## **Experience**

#### **Roster / Senior Software Engineer**

July 2017 - April 2018, Louisville, CO

Development on backend team using Phoenix web framework for Elixir. Also built authentication system, set up JSON API, and helped with product direction.

## **SpotX** / Software Engineer

April 2017 - July 2017, Boulder, CO

Full stack development with AngularJS and PHP.

### **Gloo / Software Engineer**

March 2014 - April 2017, Boulder, CO

Development on backend team using Ruby on Rails. Full stack development of analytics system in Polymer, Node.js, and Postgres.

## Mercury Payment Systems / Software Engineer

November 2011 - March 2014, Durango, CO

Developed/maintained C# based payment front-end which involved extensive low-level system troubleshooting. Developed asynchronous, end-to-end test framework and several other utilities using Node.js. Created an highly configurable website for monitoring call queues which

was used in their call center. Also created an administration panel website for managing the "Stand-In" behavior of the payment front-ends.

## Mercury Payment Systems / Quality Assurance Engineer

April 2010 - November 2011, Durango, CO

Manual and automated testing of web based and desktop payment software. Developed keyword/data/modularity driven QTP automation framework and various utility programs with C#.

# **Education**

#### Fort Lewis College / Bachelor of Arts CSIS

August 2006 - May 2010, Durango, CO

# **Projects**

Subscription based notification system in rails using ASN (ActiveSupport Notifications)

Oauth provider and consumer functionality

Deeplinking functionality for multi-app system

Analytics system frontend/backend with custom query interface in Node.js and Polymer

Plugins for processing framework in Java for extracting transaction files

End-to-end parallelized framework for payment transaction testing based in Node.js

Python based weather display for Raspberry Pi with message queueing via google talk

Modular automation framework for QTP (QuickTest Professional)

Business directory database and corresponding administrative website

#### Interests

Rock climbing

Running

Hobbyist electronics